[Music]
this is software engineering radio the
podcast for professional developers on
the web at
SE-R SE radio is brought to you by the
it computer society and by It software
Magazine online at computer.org
[Music]
software hi all welcome to this episode
of software engineering radio Our Guest
today is Adam Frank Adam is SVP product
and marketing at
armory.io Armory is focus and providing
solutions for continuous deployment at
any scale for all developers Adam has
over two decades of software development
experience he's focused on delivering
products and strategies that help
companies attain optimal business
agility welcome to this show Adam it's
great to have you here is there anything
you'd like to add to your bio before we
get started that was a fantastic
introduction thank you for having me I'm
very excited about being here optimal
business agility well that does sound
nice there at the end huh before we
start I'd like to point our guests to a
few related episodes that we have done
in the past these are episode 498 James
sool on continuous integration and
Delivery episode 567 Dave cross on gith
up actions and lastly episode 338 Brent
lter on Jenkins 2 Bill server So Adam
can you kind of help us build on episode
498 by helping all us
recap what exactly is continuous
integration continuous delivery
continuous deployment and what is the CD
is it continuous delivery or continuous
deployment in
cic well that's an evergoing debate I
would say in these days between
continuous delivery and continuous
deployment but let's start with
continuous integration first of all
that's been around for quite some time
and is absolutely a practice that
everybody needs in their software
development continuous integration is
really about producing that artifact
going through and having automated tests
and just having an artifact that is up
to the standard that you believe it
should be in a really automated fashion
continuous
delivery in a nutshell is focused on
automating the process to have a release
ready artifact so with a manual approval
in place you can then deploy that
artifact out to to your runtime
environments continuous deployment the
other CD in
cicd is really about automating that
last step so when developers are
committing their codes there's an
artifact being created out of their
continuous integration process that
artifact is being deployed out to their
runtime environments without any manual
approval now of course with continuous
deployment there are a whole bunch of
safeguards and practices that sure we'll
get into but at the end of the day it's
really about automating that deployment
of that code out to the runtime
environments so the big difference
between continuous integration and
continuous deployment is the approval
needed yeah the difference between
continuous delivery and continuous
deployment is as simple as that like I
said it's the focusing on having a
release ready and automating that
release ready so there's no manual
intervention with continuous deployment
and it's a fantastic practice we
certainly encourage everybody and it's
very attainable these days especially
with the safeguards in place like doing
Canary deployments and blue green
deployments and you know having
automated checks in place and things
like that really just orchestrating that
deployment across all of your different
runtime environments so you can have the
confidence that the change you are
making will remain safe and improve your
customers experience I think we'll get
to that a little bit in the context of
some later questions and investigations
I'd like to do around differences
between B to C and B2B however oh most
definitely at this time just focusing on
the big picture do you think there's a
big difference between implementing cicd
for a monolith versus a microservices
based product Oh great question so the
practices there are the same the
practices there are really quite similar
the difference with the microservices
and the monolith are those microservices
each have their own individual
responsibilities so you can make smaller
changes to smaller areas of your overall
experience you are delivering with the
monolith you're typically making if
you're making a change to one area it's
typically updating kind of that entire
area so a lot of people with monoliths
really get into the practice of
continuous delivery and have that manual
check in place at the end to release
that release ready artifact with a
checklist to just ensure an extra layer
of safety when it comes to the
microservices that's really where people
are starting to employ a lot more of the
continuous deployment and automation I
mean they have their own
responsibilities and you know some teams
are responsible for different
microservices so they want to continue
to move fast and iterate and that all
allows them to do that so are there any
prerequisites before somebody starts
lenting cicd you know that's a fantastic
question that we get from a lot of our
customers all the time you know when we
talking at their to prospects and when I
talk to a lot of developers they say
yeah you know we really want to do
continuous deployment but we just don't
have this integration test automated or
you know we've got a security scanning
process that we need to run so it's just
something that we're not quite ready for
when in fact I believe quite the
opposite you don't have to have
everything automated to then go and
employ continuous deployment if you
don't have an integration test automated
that's okay if you need to do some
security scanning that's okay that's
actually great we certainly encourage
that as part of orchestrating your
deployment you can have some checks in
place you can have the artifact deployed
out to the environment you can have the
integration test run and then you can
click the approve button and have that
continue on to the next environment or
the next stage within your overall
deployment that's all great you know we
encourage people we help you get there
you can get to the fully automated
process I don't think you can't just
because you don't have one piece
automated so that manual approval is
contingent on some manual Test passing
is that what you mean exactly yes yeah
if there was an integration test there
or there was some security scanning that
needed to pass successfully before it
continued on to production anything of
that nature it's really orchestrating
the checks and balances that you have in
place and when that passes then the
deployment carries on I would say the
major prerequisite to doing any type of
continuous delivery or continuous
deployment is really having a continuous
integration process in place and that's
where a lot of developers start
obviously getting that build automated
having that artifact ready that's
absolutely a prerequisite nobody would
you know don't recommend anybody jumping
straight into continuous delivery or
continuous deployment if they're not
actually practicing continuous
integration and having that build
artifact automated what about the actual
update shouldn't there be a prere of
making sure that it's a zero down time
update oh so back into the microservices
and the monolith that's a great point
zero downtime updates are absolutely a
goal for a lot of organizations a lot of
organizations you can help mitigate some
of that using traffic Management Service
meeses and things like that as part of
your deployment process certainly with
load balancers blue green deployments
kind of Shifting that traffic for users
there's a lot of things that you can do
there to really mitigate that zero
downtime and and get as close to zero
downtime as possible there are certainly
some application and development
practices that you would need to employ
as part of your application that would
live outside of some of that process
which we certainly encourage and you
know I think there are a lot of people
practicing that today we certainly are
with our SAS offerings having that zero
downtime but there's a way that you can
do it to really really mitigate it using
a number of techniques throughout your
continuous deployment process so it's it
appears it appears zero down time I
would say so back to the question I had
earlier and if you had any examples that
would be great but is the approval
process or the practice of adopting or
choosing between continuous deployment
and continuous delivery any different
for a b2c SAS and a B2B SAS we've got a
number of customers that are B2B and
then we've got a number of customers
that are B Toc I would say some of the
largest complexities that we see with B
Toc are different regulations and
geographical constraints people are
creating apps that are both on the web
on mobile phones there are a lot of
different processes and regulations that
occur within there so while they are
practicing continuous delivery and
pushing code out something like the App
Store as an example they would
absolutely have a manual process in
place to make sure that a lot of the
regulations the checks the balances are
in place before the latest version of
the that particular app is available on
the App Store I mean I'll use Snapchat
as an example Snapchat is a global
company they're in you know over a
hundred countries absolutely massive in
India and they have so many different
regulations that they need to deal with
and and they're deploying across
thousands and thousands of kubernetes
clusters as backends so they are both
practicing continuous deployment in some
areas and in different areas of the
planet you know around the globe but
certainly different areas of the
application but then continuous delivery
in other areas and you know using their
main app as an example and going through
App Store process and making sure that
every all the checks and balances are in
place there both from Apple and and both
from Snapchat they do have manual
approvals that are in place to make sure
that the changes are not breaking
changes and stay within the regulation
and customer experience that they
expecting to deliver so how does one
start the journey beginning with
identifying what is the best process
based on my unique goal or my
organization's unique goals yeah a lot
of people starts with that one team in
the organization that is really a team
that everybody looks up to you know
they're kind of a little bit more mature
a little bit more advanced in some of
their processes they've taken the time
to really hone in their integration
process they've really taken the time to
start adopting and practicing new
methodologies and adopting new
technologies so what we've seen is a lot
of people will take that poster child
team within the
organization and they'll work through
the process that they need to be able to
automate their deployment and some
nuances in there can be they require
different security scanning they require
different constraints put in so they've
got multiple environments they deploy to
the west of North America and then the
east of North America before they go out
to Europe or something of that nature
they set forth that process with that
team and then it's all automated and of
course people within the organization
are looking up to that team and that
team is now increased their velocity
even more increased their reliability
even more by really honing in and
employing continuous deployment and then
they start to roll on the next team and
the next team and the more teams that
they roll on the better and better they
get at kind of drawing out process and
adopting very similar processes we have
a very expansive customer base right now
that is really in a lot of the elite
category of development doing thousands
and thousands of deployments per day and
something that we noticed when we looked
at all of the different pipelines that
all of these different customers were
setting up was and when it comes down to
it people were really doing almost the
same four or five things so when you
start to realize that you can start to
roll teams on much faster and you start
to have process ready to go for them and
there's a lot of companies out there
that they've been able to come in and
use a single pipeline you know a single
process for a lot of this despite
different areas of their application or
what it may be and that of course has
certainly accelerated things and made
the platform Engineers life a little bit
easier as they dve process you mentioned
four or five things can you elaborate
yeah I mean integration tests are one
everybody is doing a level of
integration
testing security scanning the vast
majority of people are doing some type
of security scanning or signing for that
matter everybody's got at least three
environments from seed stage companies
that we talk to all the way up to the
largest top Fortune 100 top Fortune 50
companies everybody has at least three
stages Dev stage and production so they
need to be able to deploy to Dev do
something deploy to staging do something
and then deploy to production and in
that order those are the constraints
that they would want put in and that's
kind of the you know one of the largest
scenarios that we see out there is you
know everybody's got three and then it
grows from there three to five to 10 to
hundreds you know around the globe
different environments different regions
and things of that nature and then you
start getting into a little bit more of
the advanced use cases you start getting
into a little bit more of the blue
greens or the canaries and then
automating Canary analysis so when it
comes down to it everybody has that goal
of increasing their reliability and
moving quickly without breaking things
so they want to start by deploying to
those three environments running tests
like integration making sure that the
code is secure there no vulnerabilities
and things of that nature and then start
getting into 5% of that traffic and 10%
and 25% up to 50 and analyzing that in
an automated fashion so they know that
the change that is being rolled out is
safe and they can have that confidence
to continue pushing multiple changes and
multiple updates per day thanks Adam so
I wanted to explore a little bit the
manual approval before delivering to
production and potential cascading
effect of that so if you have multiple
services that
have a dependency meaning if my service
a has a dependency on B and B has a
dependency on C and if I have a manual
approval at what level should I do that
at the service level and if I do it at
more of a product level which includes
all the services what are the challenges
I would have I'm thinking just
constructing environments to do full end
to end testing with all the latest code
in place does my question make sense it
does absolutely we have a good amount of
customers that do have tightly coupled
services and need to make sure that
those are all updated in any type of
sequential fashion or updated
simultaneously and that includes roll
backs so if there is a roll back needed
those tightly coupled Services also need
to roll back some of the difficulties
that we've seen there with some of the
manual approvals that people had in
place
beforehand we're really making sure that
the sequence the dependencies were known
and things were done in the correct
order I mean I can take you back 15
years before that if there's even proper
continuous delivery put in place I used
to have to update this application that
we had when I was on call and there were
nine different services and you had to
update service one service two service
three service 4 all the way through
service 9 and each one had their own
manual approval each one had their own
manual testing each one had their own
manual everything and when we were
confident that one was good we went on
and updated the next one and as soon as
we found out we were on service 4 or
service 5 and the update didn't work
then we had to go back and roll
everything back because there was no
fixing it and rolling It Forward at that
point in time so there were a lot of
difficulties having that manual approval
in place like that and that's again
where some continuous deployment can
actually help or Solutions out there
hours included that enables you to
automatically update tightly coupled
services and roll back tightly coupled
Services as needed understanding those
dependencies so if somebody did have
such tight coupling then continuous
deployment is certainly a
challenge however let's say people you
know especially in a b2c SAS environment
have a much better structure where they
are able to do continuous deployment
what does this mean to the C customer
experience so the consuming company will
now be exposed to changes almost
continuously what is it mean for them to
be able to test as well as look at any
new features that are coming with the
changes being made available so I want
to step back on that just for a second
because I want to be very clear that the
best way to change a user experience is
by leveraging feature Flags you don't
want to have a feature a quarter
completed a half completed or anything
like that out there for users to stumble
upon and think that it doesn't work or
it doesn't work as it's supposed to and
you know perhaps support tickets and
bugs and things like that raised when
it's not a complete full feature so
continuous deployment is still deploying
that code out there having it ready but
when it comes to actually changing the
user experience significantly like that
we certainly recommend and using feature
Flags now smaller changes that may not
be changing the customer experience to
that dramatic effect that again you can
control using traffic shaping so you can
do it to 5% of the traffic 10% of the
traffic 25% of the traffic and make sure
that everything is working as it is
intended to and the users aren't going
to necessarily notice that level of
change but like I said when it's a
bigger feature or let's say a UI refresh
you're completely changing where Buttons
used to be you're going from a top level
nav to a leftand nav you would certainly
want to change that type of experience
with something like feature Flags so the
code is continuously deployed out there
but the actual change to the user is
done through something like feature
flagging if not you're going to have a
leftand nav and a Top Hand nav at the
same time and you know we work in a very
agile fashion and we're going to iterate
on things so having a top level nav and
a left-and nav with you know one module
in the top and one module in the left
that's going to be a very clunky user
experience they're absolutely going to
think that your application's broken in
that case so again that's where
something like feature flagging comes
into the sdlc and works really really
well so episode 498 did delve into some
detail on the feature flag and just the
complexity maybe in deciding when you
start on something is it going to need a
feature flag what's your experience on
that I think a lot of the times when
we're designing a new feature a new
experience from the vision of that and
that Northstar goal that we have for it
we can understand if there's going to be
feature Flags needed or at what level
feature Flags will be needed there's a
lot of underlying changes that you can
make to a particular feature or
implementing a new feature that may not
interrupt may not be there for the user
to experience but a lot of the times
that I've seen developers and the team
the product development team that is
creating this has a really good sense of
when the user is going to be able to
start viewing this start using this so
they know when something should be
feature flagged I mean have it as part
of your planning make it part of the
discussion make it part of the design
phases like what point are we going to
feature flag this we're going to feature
flag it right from the beginning are
there changes that we can make and then
feature flag
it is a practice that really should
happen at the onset so as maybe let's
end this section of just drilling into
testing so on the developer side and on
the integration side what are the
different kinds of test you would expect
to have in the pipeline you know and and
environments so do we talk in terms of a
unit test setup which is automated in a
Dev environment and then a
pre-production environment what are the
different kinds of environments do you
recommend and what the different levels
of testing automation do you recommend
yeah definitely unit tests absolutely
unit tests in the development
environment typically integration tests
absolutely happen in you know a
full-fledged staging environment
security scanning and security tests
often times happen in another isolated
environment one that is before your
production environment alongside
the staging environment we see quite
often as well and then of course there
are certain smoke tests and things like
that that run when the deployment
happens out to production and again with
something like Canary analysis even some
of those endtoend tests and testing some
of the user experience baselining that
metric or or you know those metrics that
are communicating back to you what the
customer is experiencing what the
latency looks like what the saturation
looks like of your particular
application and understanding that
Baseline to move forward with your
deployment to increase that traffic to
move it to from customers in the west to
customers in the East things of that
nature and then what about testing on
the consumer side of the B2B application
do I also need to have automated tests
every time the SAS provider is updating
and deploying to production is that
recommended on the consumer side things
no I mean I can't think of a single
service or application that I use as a
consumer that I have any type of tests
running I think we really have to trust
and part of that reliability and
stability and customer experience that's
being delivered to us is allowing us to
have that level of trust and it's a
incredibly competitive market and
competitive day that we live in I can
move to another service I can move to
another application very very quickly
and still achieve what I need to achieve
whatever that may be think of streaming
services as an example you know how many
streaming services are out there now you
start to have a bad experience with your
streaming provider you can move to
another streaming service very very
quickly so we have to trust and if that
trust is broken that compan is going to
pay not us we're going to move we're
going to go continue to live our life
and experience it on the be to b side
though it is more
sticky so does your answer change for
the B2B app depending on what the level
is absolutely a lot of B2B apps there
will be some level of integration with
other B2B apps and those two companies
may or may not have a relationship with
one another this may be something that
was created by these companies together
jointly there's an integration there and
you don't necessarily need to test that
if they are working together and
ensuring that the quality is there if
it's something that you created yourself
to stitch two applications together to
stitch two processes together I would
absolutely recommend testing it if you
know if there's no relationship between
the two companies and it was a third
party that created some level of
integration or something like that you
know I'd absolutely want to test it and
the larger the Enterprise the larger
that application is and the more
business critical it is you the more we
would absolutely recommend and you know
testing there as well and hence creating
an automated test
Suite yeah yeah most definitely okay
let's switch now and spend some time on
the developer experience and the tooling
maybe just starting with the evolution
of this tooling for
cicd yeah I think developer experience
is something that has certainly come to
the Forefront and if we look back at
kind of the Inception of devops bringing
development operations together back in
20072 2008 there was the whole Mantra
about creating a culture of you build it
and you own it at any cost there are a
lot of complexities a lot of
complexities with that and a lot of
things that have to be known in order to
fully own it and operate it and I think
that's really where we've seen the
evolution and the new role and
responsibility of site reliability
engineers and as of late platform
engineers site reliability engineers and
platform Engineers should still very
much work in a devops an agile manner
don't get me wrong devops is still very
much alive but now platform engineering
has kind of been that focus a lot more
on the developer experience to really
empower the developer to enable that
developer to own it and build it by
providing a platform that increases and
improves that developer experience if
you look at all the different nuances of
the software development life cycle
creating that platform that enables the
developer to deploy their code fast at a
high quality increasing reliability and
assuring their customer experience you
increase your developer experience you
are definitely going to increase your
customer experience so I think it's
something that's really come to light
over the last couple of years as
businesses try and stay more and more
competitive move faster so there's a
whole sweet of processes and tools that
kind of underly that platform to
increase and improve the developer
experience and continuous deployment is
certainly at the center of that can you
cover the tooling and the evolution
maybe at a high level yeah yeah for sure
I mean we just kind of talked about the
devops mentality that was there of build
and own it and you know first continuous
integration and continuous integration
tools and automating a lot of that
builds there's a huge market for test
tools and quality assurance security as
of you know more and more as of late has
started to shift left and become into
observability came around in about 2015
it was no longer just the ability to
monitor from the outside things that are
happening but really being able to
observe the internal of an application
from Telemetry it's creating that means
there's a massive market for
observability now hot on the he of
continuous integration was continuous
delivery and then even more automation
came in place with continuous deployment
and devops has really enabled people to
continue to move quickly but I think
more so now that developer experience is
at the Forefront and platform
engineering is starting to have a
focused responsibility on enabling and
empowering those developers you've see
them with responsibilities of providing
testing Frameworks providing continuous
integration tools providing continuous
delivery and deployment tools providing
the observability suite and framework uh
whether that's you know set between the
developer and the site reliability
engineer they are certainly looking to
improve both experiences and and you
know first and foremost the developer so
that code is of high quality and being
deployed quickly so earlier in the
podcast you mentioned customer of yours
that has hundreds or maybe thousands of
deployments to day what kind of
challenges does that create as soon as
you said that another Custer came to
mind that has over 125,000 deployments
per month they are a technology company
that's been around for many many years I
think some of the challenges that I can
think of that they have really seen we
sat down and chatted with them in a seed
Stage Company at the exact same table
and it was so interesting to hear the
complexities that they talked about
and the complexities that the sieg Stage
Company talked about and just you know
them kind of smile back and forth at
each other from time to time like
they're both crazy you know living in a
world that neither of them even remember
or can fathom I think some of the
challenges that this very large company
has experienced is they've got eight
different languages that they need to
support across hundreds of applications
they've got underlying infrastructure
that is using multiple cloud services
from serus to container services to
container services that they've built
within their own data centers they are a
company that's around the globe so
they've got multiple regions again
different regulations in different
company in in different countries so
they have got an immense amount of
complexity depending on what application
they're updates they're deploying and
where they're deploying it to so I think
part of it is really establishing that
culture
and you're going to really be able to
establish and help that Culture by
empowering your developers the more you
Empower those developers the more
they're going to get on board with the
overall culture so for these deployments
since there's such a huge volume how do
the developers track if deployment has
to be rolled back what are the metrics
they would typically use to determine
that and I assume do that automatically
yeah the most basic ones are really
looking at some of the underlying
infrastructure metrics those ones are
easy but every application is going to
have its own set of metrics and it's
really up to the application development
team that understands what those metrics
are and the experience that they're
delivering I mean you can look at things
like golden signals looking at
saturation looking at latency you know
looking at response times and things of
that nature that are certainly going to
help you establish does this need to be
rolled back you know the latency was 1
second before this change and and now
it's three seconds that could be
detrimental to the application or it
could still be okay you know that's
really up to the development team and
understanding the experience that they
are delivering so being able to look at
those metrics and understand when things
need to roll back or can continue
forward and then going even further and
doing that in an automated fashion and
having statistical analysis and machine
learning do that for you I mean that's
the ultimate price and that's very
achievable in today's world that is very
achievable with our Solutions and you
know practicing the Contin deployment
out there so how has generative AI if it
all changed this you mentioned machine
learning yeah I think generative AI in
terms of the software development life
cycle I think the area that we're seeing
the most focus in right now is code
generation part of that code generation
can be configuration generation as well
so producing different sets of of yaml
that may be needed and when we live in
the world that we live in kubernetes
really introduced us to declarative and
being able to produce some declarative
configuration has been a pretty easy
process for generative AI when it comes
to doing machine learning on Metric data
and things like that that's been around
for a number of years now you know
before this this big generative AI bang
that's been a great process that has
worked for a number of customers a
number of people a number of developers
that we have great relationships with
and and help every single day but I
think the generative AI the big booming
it right now is really the code
generation Armory is a global company
and I think one of the biggest uses that
we have it for right now as a global
company English is not the first
language for a lot of the company and
being able to have a common language
that everybody speaks within the code
using comments and things like that to
help other developers understand you
know what the thought process was and
you know what this code is supposed to
do has been really helpful it's been
great using generative AI to help write
a a lot of our comments and things like
that fast prototyping using generative
AI to to produce some levels of code for
fast prototyping has also been really
really great for us but in terms of
deployment at this stage I think we're
still very early on although I did write
an article about some prototyping and
practicing that we did a couple of
months ago so I think there is most
definitely a future Beyond declarative
that is generative when it comes to
continuous deployment so maybe let's
switch to Armory and unique aspects of
Armory solution then I read about
continuous deployment as a service what
is that can you elaborate sure Armory
started out in 2015 2016 and at that
time Netflix was one of the leading
development organizations in the world
and they had developed internally a
project called Spiner and sper quickly
became the deao continuous delivery
continuous deployment project out there
on the market so Armory adopted
commercializing sper and one of the
biggest advantages that Armory has had
over other companies is being able to
work with Elite development teams that
are kind of at the Forefront of adopting
early stage Technologies like kubernetes
early stage practices like continuous
deployment and at very large
scales I mean like we talked about
hundreds of thousands of deployments per
month across several different
environments around the globe we've been
able to learn an immense amount from our
customer base and continuous deployment
as a service is really the evolution of
that so what we knew we needed to do was
create a simpler offering that was
full-fledged in power so declarative
came along with kubernetes so CD as a
service is really a declarative
continuous deployment process that
orchestrates the deployment of that
artifact from your artifact fact repo
across all of your environments it
allows you to hook in security scanning
integration testing any different
process that you have fits directly into
your sdlc the traffic shaping that we've
been talking about the blue green the
canary all that great stuff it's all in
there it's very very powerful it is as
you can guess by the name as a service
so it also has off and arbac and things
like that all built into it so it's a
full package ready to go for any
development team any platform
engineering team that is looking to
increase and improve their developer
experience and spend more of their time
focused on their competitive Advantage
can leverage CD as a service as their CD
control plane so then you take over the
challenge of scaling if somebody is
doing hundreds of thousands of
deployments I assume you have to make
sure that your platform or your service
skills up to that oh most definitely
most definitely and part of that
Evolution we looked at other open source
projects and we saw you a lot of
difficulties with those when it in terms
of scale when it does come to some of
these larger organizations and that's
why we developed it from the ground up
and it's been so much fun developing it
from the ground up and working with some
of the the best technology companies in
the world and working with you know a
lot of seed companies at the same time
that don't have the funding or time to
employ people to build out a CD process
a CD solution based on open source
projects and and other things like that
and don't get me wrong we are huge
Advocates of Open Source we're still
very much contributing back to several
open source projects that are out there
big big fans of the cncf and everything
that's happened there as well so I think
there's a a big bright feature for CD as
a service the community in general and
people who are getting started with
continuous deployment so is there a
difference in recommendation to teams to
that are getting started depending on
how many different products that they
want to integrate and build cicd
pipelines for versus some team that's
just getting started and has a very
small maybe a couple of services that
they will be testing the more tools you
have the more it's going to take to
manage them so people and the more
they're going to cost whether it's an
open source project and you need to hire
people there's some costs there ramp up
time knowledge all that kind of good
stuff or it's some type of subscription
service so the more you have the more it
is going to cost you so we absolutely
see ourselves included tool
rationalization and consolidation and
all that good stuff so I think whether
you have a couple of services or whether
you have a hundred Services I think you
should always try and keep your platform
as tight as possible so you can manage
it easier you can help keep your costs
down and there are some Fantastic Tools
out there you know open cost is a great
open source project Cloud zero is an
example that can help you really manage
your costs at the same time not just
your infrastructure but translating
those to your business costs and
everything that you have in and around
your platform and what you are serving
out so you did talk a little bit in the
context of generative AI on what's in
the future but you want to elaborate and
talk about some other stuff that you're
looking at at Armory one of the big
things that we are working on right now
that we're incredibly excited about
comes from the learnings that we've had
with a lot of these customers kubernetes
has taken the World by storm but every
single customer that we have and every
single prospect that we've talked to has
kubernetes and something else and
kubernetes is also complex so a lot of
people don't have the time and and
energy to invest in it so they move to
simpler container services like ECS
Amazon's ECS as an example so there is
still very much a large world out there
that requires deploying to more than
just kubernetes so we are actually
working right now releasing it very soon
on our next Target which is Lambda and
building that out so people can build
additional targets that they need as
Armory continues to build out more and
more targets so people can deploy from a
single platform to more than just
kubernetes they can deploy to kubernetes
they can deploy to Lambda they can
deploy to ECS and so on and so forth
that's something that we're working on
in the near- term right now that we are
very very excited about and then of
course security supply chain is a big
one right now and that's a story that we
haven't really told Yet full capability
is there but it's a story we haven't
really told yet and making sure that the
code that you are deploying to
development the code that you have
written is signed and that is indeed the
code that is making it out to production
is another one of those shiftleft
security things that's very very
important and it's just a story that we
haven't quite told yet further down the
road yeah absolutely the generative AI
stuff is very very
exciting we have absolutely started to
play with it to the point where you've
got
Brownfield first everybody's got some
level of infrastructure in place so
simply providing the account information
the credentials to that infrastructure
to any tooling and letting the
generative AI connect
them and then simply using text to say
this is going to deploy or deploy this
deploy this using blue green or even
letting the generative AI figure out
whether blue green or Canary is the
proper strategy there it's really
exciting stuff to see what we're doing
Brown Field's different there's a lot
more complexities there when there is no
infrastructure or nothing in place I
think that'll take a little bit longer
to figure out but needless to say it's
still very much an area that is being
explored uh Greenfield sorry I think I
said Brownfield there twice but I meant
Greenfield in the first on the second
one there go Adam do you think there's
any key topic that we missed talking
about today that you'd like to cover no
I don't think so I've had a ton of fun
today there was covered a lot of ground
when it comes to continuous deployment I
think this is going to be a fantastic
episode for all the listeners out there
and you know I'm certainly excited to
come back and and do it again and
continue talking about developer
experience perhaps or platform
engineering to incredibly exciting
topics again Adam how can people contact
you people can reach me anytime at adam.
Frank that's a
d.f an k at
armory.io a m o r
y. thanks for listening to SC radio and
educational program brought to you by It
software magazine for more about the
podcast including other episodes visit
our website at se-
radio.net to provide feedback you can
comment on each episode on the website
or reach us on LinkedIn Facebook Twitter
or through our slack Channel at
seo. slack.com you can also email us at
team
scr.cr is licensed under Creative
Commons license
2.5 thanks for